Vinoth Sadhasivan

Uthradam House, Near SUT Royal hospital, Pongumoodu, Ulloor, Trivandrum Kerala-695011

Mobile: +91 9446919834

Email: Vinoth.Sadhasivan@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL OBJECTIVE:

Accomplished, motivated and versatile Software Implementation professional; IT Coordinator, Implementation Executive with 5 years of experience in the Hospitality industry, seeks the next big career challenge and an opportunity to apply his knowledge and expertise on a larger scale.

CORE SKILLS:

- 1. I have a very flexible working attitude with a constant awareness to produce the highest results in my work.
- 2. I have a strong background in interacting with the Hospitality/Financial clients and to analyze the designed requirements to implement the solutions using the respective products.
- 3. I pride myself on my problem solving abilities and capability to observe areas needing improvement and change.
- 4. I perform very well under pressure whilst remaining composed and courteous whilst completing my tasks.
- 5. Interfacing with key clients for mapping requirements, making presentations and delivering need based product solutions.
- 6. Maintaining excellent relations with clients to generate avenues for additional business

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

• Opera PMS and S&C, Micros POS (Installation, Configuration & Training)

- Digital Signage, IPTV (Installation, Training and Support)
- Exposures in Internet tools like PHP, XML, HTML, UML and Java Scripts
- Exposures in RDBMS tools like Oracle 9i, Ms SQL Server and Ms Access
- Exposures in C++, Visual Basic, JAVA, MYSQL and so on.
- Well versed in Operating Systems such as Windows X and Linux Environment and Apache Server.
- Well versed in WebEx Remote Support and other remote site support

SOFT SKILLS:

Excellent in:

- Communication
- Team Management
- Presentation
- Customer Support and Relations

EDUCATIONAL HISTORY:

Overall Academic Assessment: "B +" Grade

- 1. M.B.A, (Masters of Business Administration—International Hospitality and Tourism Management) (Full time) IMI (Affiliated to Manchester Metropolitan University, London, United Kingdom), Switzerland, June 2005—June 2006
- **2. B.Sc**, in **Applied Mathematics and Computer Applications**, Annamalai University, Chidambaram, India, July 1996- May 1999
- 3. 12th, Sri Ramakrishna Matriculation Higher Secondary School, Karamadai, Coimbatore, June 1994— June 1996
- 4. 10th, Metro Matriculation Higher Secondary School, Mettupalayam, April 1992

ADDITIONAL QUALIFICATIONS:

Assessment: Grade "A"

WAMP (Diploma in Windows Apache MySQL PHP), Computer Software College (CSC), Coimbatore, India, May 2009--August 2009

HDNC/GNIIT (Honors/Graduate Diploma in Network Computing Solutions), NIIT, Coimbatore, India, June 1996--June 1998

WORK HISTORY AND EXPERIENCE:

Total Years of Work Experience in Hospitality Software Implementation: 5 + Years Professional Work History

- Worked as an Associate Implementation Consultant-Hospitality Software (HBSi) from January 2013 – June 2013, IBS Software Services, Techno park, Trivandrum, Kerala
- 2. Worked as an **Assistant Implementation/Support Engineer** from January 2011 to September 2012 in **Techno Q, Hospitality Solutions for Micros Fidelio**, Doha, Qatar
- Worked as a IT Software Implementation/Supporting Executive in The Northolme Resort & Spa (Hilton Property), Seychelles December 2007— January 2011
- 4. Worked as a **Desk Executive** in **The Hotel Residency, Coimbatore**, India, July 2006—November 2007

Main Duties and Responsibilities:

- Understanding the requirements and needs of the clients, analyse the information's
 and set up the skill for up selling the Micros Fidelio products like wifi, scanner and
 so on.
- 2. Based on the requirements, identify the client's servers (Application, Database and Interface server) and set a standard Micros product documentation to install the products in the sequence (OS, Antivirus and any other supporting tools before installing the Micros Products).
- 3. Installing, Configuring, Testing and maintaining the software products (Hospitality/Financial ERP and so on)
- 4. After installing the Opera PMS in application server and Oracle in data base server, try to upgrade the PMS later versions (v5.0) if it is necessary in the appropriate systems.

- 5. Handling the configuration schedule as per sequence starting from the Rooms, Reservations, Accounts, Housekeeping, Night Audit and so on, if it is necessary take the guidance from the respective department staffs from the Hotels.
- 6. Prepare and implement a week Training Schedule for the Staffs for the respective departments Rooms, Reservation, Accounts, and HK and so on
- 7. Coordinate with the Micros and other third party team members in ensuring a smooth and perfect interface has been done with Opera PMS.
- 8. Before the live process (Client), ensure to complete any pending work has to be done from the above process.
- 9. Handle and take care of the Client's live day starting from the Rooms till the end of the day (Night audit) process smoothly.
- 10. Prepare and fill the Micros Standard Project Completion report and ensure it has been signed properly from the client before submitting to the team leader or the Project manager.
- 11. Handle any other issues after the project completion and make ensure to solve the issue at the quick time.
- 12. Handle online and offline support issues after project completion and give the detailed weekly, monthly report to the team leader. (Update the issues in Micros standard support site).
- 13. Co-operates in the performance of any reasonable task requested by the Management.
- 14. Handling the customer related queries and supporting the issues and finding the defects through iDemand gateway
- 15. Configuring, Testing and Installing the products in the clients environment with necessary troubleshooting skills and fixing the defects found in the production and as well as in UAT Environment.
- 16. Tracking customer feed back on a monthly basis and preparing reports.

PERSONAL DETAILS:

Date of Birth: 28/05/1977

Nationality: Indian

Marital status: Single

Passport Number: E6108617

Current Salary: 25,000 INR /Month

Expected Salary: Negotiable Notice period: Immediate

Languages Known: Malayalam, Tamil, English, French

Reason for Leaving: Finished Contract period

Visited Countries: Switzerland, France, Qatar, Germany, UAE, Sri Lanka, Seychelles

Hobbies: Music, Cricket, Meditation

PROFESSIONAL REFERENCES:

1. Dr Roy C Wood FHEA, FIH

Professor, Breda, the Netherlands, Mobile: 0031 627824582

Off. Email: Wood.R@nhtv.nl

2. Mr. Raj Kumar Rao,

Senior Hospitality Consultant, Prologic First Hospitality Software Solutions

Email: gururaj@prologicfirst.ae, Mobile: +971 50 320 6742

3. Mr. Francis KP, General Manager, Tissa's Inn Hotel, Fort Kochi, Cochin, Kerala, India,

Mobile: +91 98470 44845, Email: kpfrancis@gmail.com

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that the above-mentioned details are true and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.

PLACE: Trivandrum, India

DATE: 01.10.2013 (Vinoth.S)